<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TelegraphNews 2.0 - News</title>
    <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/mobilerss/</link>
    <description>TelegraphNews 2.0 - News</description>
    <ttl>1</ttl>
    <lastBuildDate>2011-06-24 12:13:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">99796019-c2e7-40e5-b1bc-2f37d5ad50fb</guid>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/economics/8596245/Eurozone-debt-crisis-poses-biggest-threat-to-UK-stability.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 11:15:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <title>Eurozone debt crisis poses biggest threat to UK stability</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Exposure could lead to a "crisis of confidence", Mervyn King warns 
  as Financial Policy Committee publishes its inaugural report.]]></description>
      <media-thumbnail url="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01929/mervyn_1929202g.jpg" width="140" height="90" />
      <media-content medium="document">
        <media-description><![CDATA[<div class="pubDate">Fri, 24 Jun 2011 11:15:21 +0100</div><div class="subTitle">Eurozone debt crisis poses biggest threat to UK stability</div><div style="padding-top:5px;margin-bottom:10px">The eurozone debt crisis poses the "most material and immediate threat" to the UK's financial stability, according to a report by Sir Mervyn King's Financial Policy Committee.</div><img src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01929/mervyn_1929202e.jpg" onerror="ImageErrorHandler(this)" height="187" width="300" alt="Eurozone debt crisis poses biggest threat to UK stability" />
                      <div id="offlineImg" style="display:none">Photo not displayed in offline mode</div><div class="caption">Mervyn King, the governor of the Bank of England</div><p>
"Sovereign and banking strains are the most material and immediate threat," 
  the committee, chaired by the Bank of England governor, said in its 
  inaugural report. 
</p><p>
The committee called for banks to improve their disclosure of sovereign and 
  bank sector exposure and also warned that authorities needed to keep a 
  closer eye on the explosion of "opaque" products such as exchange 
  traded funds (ETFs), which banks increasingly use to raise funds. 
</p><p>
It follows an overnight victory for David Cameron in preventing British 
  taxpayers' money being used to bail out Greece. 
</p><p>
At a European Union summit in Brussels, the Prime Minister won a fight with 
  Angela Merkel, the German Chancellor, to keep Britain out of any new rescue 
  package. 
</p><p>
Germany had wanted to use money from the European Financial Stability 
  Mechanism to bail out Greece. Britain is a contributor and has no veto on 
  how its &euro;11.85billion (&pound;10.5billion) funds are used. 
</p><p>
But Herman Van Rompuy, the EU president, said that the EFSM would "not be 
  part of the package". 
</p><p>
Speaking at a news conference hours later, Sir Mervyn King said 
  uncertaintainty over exposure to countries such as Greece could lead to a "crisis 
  of confidence", which posed a bigger risk than direct exposure. 
</p><p>
"There is always uncertainty about the scale of exposures, which 
  counter-parties out there are the ones which are heavily exposed," he 
  said. 
</p><p>
"That uncertainty can lead at various points for funders of banks...to 
  draw back and there can be a crisis of confidence in sentiment in which 
  people say 'I simply don't understand the complexity of the 
  interconnectedness of these exposures and I just won't take the risk of 
  lending'. And that is the bigger risk, I think." 
</p><p>
Mr King also said that the ongoing crisis in Greece was not a matter of 
  liquidity, but solvency, and a build-up of large amounts of debt: 
</p><p>
"Right through this crisis...an awful lot of people wanted to believe 
  that this was a crisis of liquidity. It wasn't, it isn't. And until we 
  accept that we will never find an answer to it. It was a crisis based on 
  solvency or to be more precise, the build up of very large amounts of debt 
  where concerns crept in on the ability of the borrowers to repay that debt," 
  he said. 
</p><p>
The report came as EU leaders scramble to avert a Greek debt default that 
  would send shockwaves through international markets. 
</p><p>
Greece 
  secured the backing of European leaders late last night for its 
  five-year austerity plan, which Greek ministers will vote on next Tuesday. 
</p><p>
Britain's benchmark FTSE 100 index opened up more than 1pc as Greece secured 
  the backing of European leaders late last night for its five-year austerity 
  plan, which Greek ministers will vote on next Tuesday. 
</p><p>
Markets also rallied in Asia, with the Hang Seng index in Hong Kong climbing 
  1.8pc as Chinese Premier Wen Jiabao said he was confident that price rises 
  would be kept firmly under control this year. 
</p><p>
Speaking in Prague before flying to Brussels, Mr Cameron said it would be "quite 
  wrong" to ask Britain to contribute to rescuing Greece, while German 
  officials said the stability mechanism should be used. 
</p><p>
Mr Cameron will also use the summit to argue that the EU should exempt small 
  firms from new red tape. "This is the right outcome for the British 
  taxpayer," said a Downing Street source. 
</p><p>
Earlier this week, aware of the potential domestic outcry if Britain had to 
  stump up billions for Greece, Chancellor George Osborne told fellow EU 
  finance ministers at talks in Luxembourg that the UK did not expect to be 
  called upon. 
</p><p>
Flying to the summit for talks over dinner, Mr Cameron reinforced the message, 
  saying that the UK wanted to see a healthy single currency - but one which 
  dealt with its problems within the club of 17 eurozone member states. 
</p><p>
When the eurozone suffered, the UK suffered, Mr Cameron acknowledged, and the 
  UK would fulfil its financial obligations as a contributor to any 
  International Monetary Fund support for the troubled Greek economy - to the 
  tune of about one billion euros in loan guarantees. 
</p>]]></media-description>
      </media-content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">98383ffa-247f-4858-aa33-8499cf59bd58</guid>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/health/healthnews/8594677/Fatal-cocktail-of-common-drugs-putting-elderly-at-risk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 22:01:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <title>Fatal cocktail of common drugs putting elderly at risk</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of thousands of older people put at increased risk of death by taking 
  combinations of common medicines.]]></description>
      <media-thumbnail url="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/elderly_1928562g.jpg" width="140" height="90" />
      <media-content medium="document">
        <media-description><![CDATA[<div class="pubDate">Thu, 23 Jun 2011 22:01:55 +0100</div><div class="subTitle">Fatal cocktail of common drugs putting elderly at risk</div><div style="padding-top:5px;margin-bottom:10px">Hundreds of thousands of older people are being put at increased risk of death or developing dementia by taking combinations of common medicines to treat routine illnesses, according to a new study.</div><img src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/elderly_1928562e.jpg" onerror="ImageErrorHandler(this)" height="187" width="300" alt="Fatal cocktail of common drugs putting elderly at risk" />
                      <div id="offlineImg" style="display:none">Photo not displayed in offline mode</div><div class="caption">The drugs, thought to be used by half of over-65s in Britain, can worsen dementia</div><p>
Well-known brands of hay fever tablets, painkillers and sleeping pills pose a 
  previously unknown threat to people&rsquo;s health when taken together, British 
  scientists claim.
</p><p>
Many are available over the counter at pharmacies as well as being prescribed 
  by GPs, nurses and chemists.  
</p><p>
Today the scientists behind the study call for doctors to recognise how 
  dangerous these drug combinations can be and to prescribe harmless 
  alternatives instead.
</p><p>
Researchers from the University of East Anglia and the University of Kent 
  identified 80 widely used medications that, when used in combination, were 
  found to increase the risk of serious health problems.
</p><p>
The drugs, including common allergy treatments Piriton and Zantac, as well as 
  Seroxat, an anti-depressant, are thought to be used by half of the 10&thinsp;
  million over-65s in Britain. Many of the drugs, when taken in combination, 
  were found to more than treble an elderly patient&rsquo;s chance of dying within 
  two years.
</p><p>
Common bladder medications, heart drugs, eye drops and asthma treatments were 
  also among those found to pose a risk.
</p><p>
All the drugs work by blocking a key chemical in the nervous system called 
  acetylcholine.
</p><p>
The researchers placed each of the drugs into one of three groups based on how 
  effectively they blocked acetylcholine. The more effective the drug was in 
  blocking the chemical, the more dangerous it was in high doses.
</p><p>
The most dangerous included the antihistamines chlorphenamine (used in the 
  brand Piriton) and promethazine (used in Phenergan), the anti-depressant 
  paroxetine (used in Seroxat) and the incontinence drug oxybutynin (used in 
  Ditropan).
</p><p>
The heartburn drug ranitidine (used in Zantac), beta blocker Atenolol, the 
  painkiller codeine and some eye drops were among the drugs in the mildest 
  category.
</p><p>
Low-risk drugs were graded one point while high-risk drugs were graded three. 
  The study found that patients who took a combination of drugs that added up 
  to four points or more &mdash; such as a high-risk antihistamine combined with 
  low-risk eye drops &mdash; had a 20 per cent chance of dying within two years, 
  compared with just seven per cent for over-65s who did not take anything. 
</p><p>
The risk of dying increased by a further 25 per cent for each additional point 
  accumulated, the study published in the Journal of the American Geriatrics 
  Society, concluded.
</p><p>
The scientists suggest that the combination of treatments could also 
  exacerbate dementia. In patients showing early signs of mental impairment 
  high doses could &ldquo;tip them over&rdquo; into a more confused state, they said.
</p><p>
Previous research has shown that acetylcholine-blocking drugs could have a 
  harmful impact on the brain. 
</p><p>
But the new study, which looked at data collected over 20 years, is the first 
  to examine the cumulative effect of the medications. It shows for the first 
  time that mixing drugs has a significant impact on a patient&rsquo;s chance of 
  death.
</p><p>
The study also identified the risk in a far greater range of drugs than had 
  previously been documented, meaning that GPs may have been prescribing pills 
  to patients without knowing the potentially deadly side-effects of combining 
  medication. Ian Maidment, one of the researchers and a pharmacist at Kent 
  University, said: &ldquo;What is really the problem is the additive effect. It is 
  the cumulative burden which is very damaging.
</p><p>
&ldquo;It is not just the obvious medicines, it is things like heart drugs and 
  antihistamines, and lots of doctors and nurses and pharmacists may not be 
  aware that these medicines have this problem.&rdquo; 
</p><p>
Researchers examined the medication records of more than 13,000 people aged 65 
  or older over two decades and found 48 per cent were using at least one of 
  the drugs on the list. 
</p><p>
Dr Chris Fox, of the University of East Anglia, said: &ldquo;In the future doctors 
  may use this tool to reduce their patient&rsquo;s score below four and that&rsquo;s 
  fine, but above that is the danger area.&rdquo;
</p><p>
The risk, the scientists said, was that patients, particularly those with 
  dementia, may be regularly taking over-the-counter drugs that their doctor 
  is unaware of, or which they do not really need, bringing their dosage up to 
  a dangerous level.
</p><p>
Mr Maidment added: &ldquo;With dementia, these drugs are particularly risky in the 
  early stages, which we call mild cognitive impairment, where the brain is 
  just at a tipping point. This extra insult can tip people over or worsen 
  dementia.&rdquo;
</p><p>
All medications, including those that are available over the counter, should 
  be reviewed regularly by expert clinicians to prevent potential risks, he 
  added.
</p><p>
Dr Fox said &ldquo;hundreds of thousands&rdquo; of elderly people in Britain could be 
  putting themselves at risk from the drugs but that more research was needed 
  to explain the exact cause.
</p><p>
Instead of stopping their medication or rushing to the doctor, patients should 
  seek their doctor&rsquo;s advice at their next routine appointment, he said.
</p><p>
Rebecca Wood, the chief executive of Alzheimer&rsquo;s Research UK, said: &ldquo;Further 
  investigation needs to establish exactly how and why (these) drugs are 
  increasing mortality, which might offer clues to safer drug design.&rdquo;
</p><p>
Dr Tim Chico, an honorary consultant 
</p><p>
cardiologist at the University of Sheffield, said: &ldquo;All drugs have possible 
  side-effects, but the results of this study should not lead anyone to stop 
  current medications without discussing this with their doctor first &hellip; it is 
  important to balance the proven benefits against the risk of side-effects.&rdquo;
</p><p>
The report said that an increase in the use of medication in recent years 
  meant the number of people affected could be even higher than estimated. 
</p><p>
A spokesman for the Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency said: 
  &ldquo;Our priority is to ensure that patients are taking acceptably safe 
  medicines. All medicines have side-effects &mdash; no effective medicine is 
  without risk.
</p><p>
&ldquo;It is important for people taking anticholinergic medicines not to stop 
  taking them. If they have any questions or concerns then they should contact 
  their doctor in the first instance.&rdquo;
</p><p>
GlaxoSmithKline and Sanofi-aventis, which manufacture some of the drugs in the 
  report, declined to comment.
</p>]]></media-description>
      </media-content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">a11e2500-e7fa-4a83-b4d9-8c43e31a967e</guid>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/al-qaeda/8595814/Seized-mobile-phone-suggests-Osama-bin-Laden-link-to-Pakistani-intelligence.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 06:58:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <title>Seized mobile phone suggests Osama bin Laden link to Pakistani intelligence </title>
      <description><![CDATA[Mobile phone belonging to bin Laden's courier had contacts for group linked to 
  Pakistan's intelligence agency.]]></description>
      <media-thumbnail url="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01901/osama2_1901562g.jpg" width="140" height="90" />
      <media-content medium="document">
        <media-description><![CDATA[<div class="pubDate">Fri, 24 Jun 2011 06:58:39 +0100</div><div class="subTitle">Seized mobile phone suggests Osama bin Laden link to Pakistani intelligence</div><div style="padding-top:5px;margin-bottom:10px">A mobile phone belonging to Osama bin Laden's trusted courier recovered in the US raid last month that killed both men contained contacts to a militant group linked to Pakistan's intelligence agency, according to reports.</div><img src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01901/osama2_1901562e.jpg" onerror="ImageErrorHandler(this)" height="187" width="300" alt="Seized mobile phone suggests Osama bin Laden link to Pakistani intelligence" />
                      <div id="offlineImg" style="display:none">Photo not displayed in offline mode</div><div class="caption">The CIA has spent much of the past month processing the intelligence from the bin Laden raid</div><p>
In a story posted on the New York Times website, senior American officials 
  said the discovery indicates that bin Laden used the group, 
  Harakat-ul-Mujahedeen, as part of his support network inside Pakistan.
</p><p>
It raises questions about whether the group and others helped shelter and 
  support the al-Qaeda 
  leader on behalf of Pakistan's spy agency.
</p><p>
The officials and analysts told the Times that Pakistan's intelligence agency 
  had mentored Harakat and allowed it to operate in Pakistan for at least 20 
  years.
</p><p>
In tracing the calls on the phone, US analysts determined that Harakat 
  commanders had called Pakistani intelligence officials. 
</p><p>
However, the US officials that there was no "smoking gun" showing 
  that Pakistan's spy agency had protected bin Laden.
</p><p>
The discovery also may help shed light on where bin Laden travelled after he 
  slipped away from US forces in the Tora Bora region of Afghanistan nearly 10 
  years ago.
</p><p>
Harakat has deep roots in the area around Abbottabad, analysts familiar with 
  the group told the Times. Its leaders have strong ties with both al-Qaeda 
  and Pakistani intelligence, known as Inter-Services Intelligence.
</p><p>
The senior American officials did not identify the commanders whose numbers 
  were in the courier's phone but said the militants were in South Waziristan, 
  where al-Qaeda and other groups had been based for years. Harakat's network 
  would have allowed bin Laden to pass on messages and money to al-Qaeda 
  members there and in other parts of Pakistan's tribal areas.
</p><p>
Bin Laden and his courier, Ibrahim Saeed Ahmed, were discovered by US 
  intelligence through a chance interception of a phone call made by Ahmed. 
  That set in motion the secret CIA search of the Abbottabad region, 
  culminating with the May 2 raid by Navy SEALs that killed bin Laden, Ahmed's 
  brother Abrar and two other people.
</p><p>
Harakat chief Fazle-ur-Rahman Khalil last month dismissed suggestions that he 
  may have been in touch with bin Laden while the al-Qaeda leader was hiding 
  in Abbottabad.
</p><p>
"It is 100 percent wrong, it's rubbish," Khalil said. "Osama 
  did not have contact with anybody." 
</p>]]></media-description>
      </media-content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">a5b0dc3b-721f-4f07-8ebc-fc559d200910</guid>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/crime/8595522/Milly-Dowler-police-knocked-on-Levi-Bellfields-door-11-times-he-stayed-free-to-strike-again.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 21:55:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <title>Milly Dowler: police knocked on Levi Bellfield's door 11 times - he stayed free to strike again</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Families of Levi Bellfield's later victims question whether their daughters 
  would still be alive were it not for police errors.]]></description>
      <media-thumbnail url="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/bellfield_1928324g.jpg" width="140" height="90" />
      <media-content medium="document">
        <media-description><![CDATA[<div class="pubDate">Thu, 23 Jun 2011 21:55:32 +0100</div><div class="subTitle">Milly Dowler: police knocked on Levi Bellfield's door 11 times – he stayed free to strike again</div><div style="padding-top:5px;margin-bottom:10px">For more than two years after Milly Dowler’s body was discovered in woodland in 2002, Surrey police laboured in vain over one of the country’s most notorious unsolved murders.</div><img src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/bellfield_1928324e.jpg" onerror="ImageErrorHandler(this)" height="187" width="300" alt="Milly Dowler: police knocked on Levi Bellfield's door 11 times – he stayed free to strike again" />
                      <div id="offlineImg" style="display:none">Photo not displayed in offline mode</div><div class="caption">Levi Bellfield went on to kill two women</div><p>
Despite identifying 256 possible suspects and speaking to 5,600 potential 
  witnesses, they were no closer to finding the 13 year-old&rsquo;s killer and the 
  inquiry was going nowhere. Then, on Nov 10, 2004, one of the detectives on 
  the murder squad took a phone call from a colleague in the Metropolitan 
  Police that would turn the investigation on its head.
</p><p>
One of the officers investigating the murders of Amelie Delagrange and Marsha 
  McDonnell in London had noticed that the prime suspect, a wheel-clamper 
  called Levi Bellfield, had once lived near Station Avenue, Walton-on-Thames, 
  the road where Milly was last seen alive. Over the months that followed, 
  detectives became convinced that Bellfield was Milly&rsquo;s killer. They also 
  discovered, to their horror, that he had been under their noses all along, 
  but had never been interviewed because he managed to avoid them on the 11 
  occasions they knocked on his door during house-to-house inquiries.
</p><p>
It meant he remained free to kill Miss McDonnell, 19, in 2003 and Miss 
  Delagrange, 22, in 2004, as well as attempting to murder another woman. The 
  investigation had been plagued by bad luck from the outset. Milly had got 
  off her train home from school, one stop before her usual station of 
  Hersham, on March 21, 2002, after friends asked her to join them for chips 
  in a caf&eacute;.
</p><p>
After phoning her father at 3.47pm to say she would be back in half an hour, 
  she started walking home and was seen walking down Station Avenue at 4.15pm 
  by a friend who was waiting at a bus stop. It was the last time anyone saw 
  her alive.
</p><p>
A CCTV camera further down the road did not pick her up, suggesting she had 
  been abducted shortly after passing the bus stop. Yet, on a busy road on a 
  spring afternoon, no one saw what happened. In the early days, detectives 
  focused much of their energy on investigating whether Milly&rsquo;s father, Bob, 
  could have been responsible for her abduction. During a search of the family 
  home, police had found a large quantity of bondage gear in the loft. One 
  possibility was that she had been lured into a house on Station Avenue or 
  one of the adjacent streets, and officers began house-to-house inquiries.
</p><p>
One of those properties was 24, Collingwood Place, the home of Bellfield. 
  Repeated attempts were made to contact the occupant, but despite speaking to 
  a new tenant who answered the door on the 11th visit by police, officers 
  left without establishing who had lived there at the time of Milly&rsquo;s 
  disappearance.
</p><p>
There were repeated sightings of Milly that suggested she might still be 
  alive. But on Sept 18, 2002, came the news the Dowler family had been 
  dreading. Milly&rsquo;s remains were found by mushroom pickers in Yateley Heath 
  Woods in Hampshire. For the next two years the investigation foundered, 
  until the breakthrough phone call from Scotland Yard. As detectives began to 
  look into Bellfield&rsquo;s background they discovered he drove a red Daewoo Nexia 
  car at the time of the murder. A trawl through CCTV footage showed a red 
  Daewoo driving on Station Avenue at 4.32pm on the day Milly was abducted.
</p><p>
Detectives originally tried to charge Bellfield with Milly&rsquo;s murder in 2006, 
  but were told there was not enough evidence. It was only in March last year, 
  when a CCTV expert was able to prove that Milly must have gone missing 
  almost directly outside Bellfield&rsquo;s flat, that he was charged with her 
  murder.
</p>]]></media-description>
      </media-content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">cd5349d7-0c5c-420a-978b-2a4b35c0febf</guid>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/barackobama/8595566/Military-chiefs-turn-their-fire-on-Barack-Obama-over-Afghanistan-withdrawal-plan.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 22:53:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <title>Military chiefs turn their fire on Barack Obama over Afghanistan withdrawal plan </title>
      <description><![CDATA[America's military leaders brand Barack Obama's 2015 withdrawal plan as 'more 
  aggressive' and riskier than their own.]]></description>
      <media-thumbnail url="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/Petraeus_1928950g.jpg" width="140" height="90" />
      <media-content medium="document">
        <media-description><![CDATA[<div class="pubDate">Thu, 23 Jun 2011 22:53:55 +0100</div><div class="subTitle">Military chiefs turn their fire on Barack Obama over Afghanistan withdrawal plan</div><div style="padding-top:5px;margin-bottom:10px">America's military leaders have distanced themselves from President's Barack Obama's plan to withdraw 33,000 troops from Afghanistan by next September, branding the drawdown timetable as more hasty and riskier than the one they proposed.</div><img src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/Petraeus_1928950e.jpg" onerror="ImageErrorHandler(this)" height="187" width="300" alt="Military chiefs turn their fire on Barack Obama over Afghanistan withdrawal plan" />
                      <div id="offlineImg" style="display:none">Photo not displayed in offline mode</div><div class="caption">General David Petraeus testifies before the Senate (Select) Intelligence Committee</div><p>
General David Petraeus, the Nato commander in Afghanistan, told Senators: "The 
  ultimate decision was a more aggressive formulation, if you will, in terms 
  of the timeline than what we had recommended."
</p><p>
Admiral Mike Mullen, chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and the most senior 
  United States military commander, used a hearing before the House Armed 
  Services Committee to reveal a significant breach between Mr Obama and the 
  senior officers he charged with defeating the Taliban in Afghanistan. 
</p><p>
"The president's decisions are more aggressive and incur more risk than I 
  was originally prepared to accept," he told a House of Representatives 
  committee hearing. 
</p><p>
Gen Petraeus said his recommendation had been based on his desire for a full 
  complement of troops for two more summer fighting seasons. Under Mr Obama's 
  new orders, a third of the current force will have returned before the end 
  of the 2011 fighting season. 
</p><p>
He added that there were "broader considerations beyond just those of a 
  military commander" and that "with the decision made, obviously I 
  support that". 
</p><p>
Robert Gates, the Pentagon chief, said that there was debate in the White 
  House about "not only the situation on the ground in Afghanistan but 
  also political sustainability here at home". 
</p><p>
Mr Obama's plan drew heavily on advice from Joe Biden, the vice president, who 
  has long favoured a "counter terrorism" rather than a 
  manpower-heavy "counter insurgency" strategy. 
</p><p>
"More force for more time is, without doubt, the safer course. But that 
  does not necessarily make it the best course. Only the President, in the 
  end, can really determine the acceptable level of risk we must take," 
  Adml Mullen said. 
</p><p>
Senator Lindsey Graham, a Republican, said: "Petraeus loses, Biden wins. 
  And I respect the vice president, but I think that we have undercut a 
  strategy that was working. I think the 10,000 troops leaving this year is 
  going to make this more difficult."
</p><p>
In his speech, Mr Obama, who did not mention Gen Petraeus, told Americans that "the 
  tide of war is receding" and that after a decade of conflict in Iraq 
  and Afghanistan "these long wars will come to a responsible end". 
</p><p>
Now that "the light of a secure peace can be seen in the distance" 
  in Afghanistan, it was "time to focus on nation building here at home". </p><p>
The comments of Adml Mullen and Gen Petraeus were carefully phrased but 
  clearly calculated to express a rare public disagreement between Mr Obama 
  and his top brass. 
</p><p>
A rift with Gen Petraeus, who commanded the successful Iraq surge, is revered 
  by many members of Congress and has been floated as a potential Republican 
  presidential candidate in 2016, could have serious political ramifications 
  for Mr Obama. 
</p><p>
The Pentagon fought a rearguard action to prevent the surge force ordered into 
  Afghanistan by Mr Obama in December 2009 from being pulled out by early 
  spring next year but the withdrawal plan announced by Mr Obama, which had 
  initially been tabled as a "compromise" by Mr Gates was not 
  endorsed by Gen Petraeus. 
</p><p>
There were reports of heated discussions during the month before Mr Obama's 
  prime-time speech on Wednesday night. Gen Petraeus characterised them as "vigorous" 
  and "healthy debate". 
</p><p>
White House officials, aware of the soaring costs of the war and its 
  questionable progress could be a political liability in the 2012 election, 
  are said to have clashed with Gen Petraeus, who argued that with more time 
  he could repeat his success in Iraq. 
</p><p>
Mr Obama rejected the Petraeus proposal to shift thousands of troops to from 
  southern Afghanistan, which has been largely pacified, to the east in order 
  to build a counter-insurgency campaign there. He also refused to bow to Gen 
  Petraeus's request to keep some of the 33,000 troops in Afghanistan until 
  2013. 
</p><p>
Seeking to avoid an ugly public row, Mr Gates confirmed that Gen Petraeus had 
  wanted a slower drawdown but added that he was "not aware of a single 
  general ever in history that did not want more troops and more time". 
</p><p>
Nearly 70,000 American troops will remain in Afghanistan even after the 
  reductions announced by Mr Obama. This is twice the number when he took 
  office in January 2009. 
</p><p>
Michele Flournoy, Undersecretary of Defense, told members of Congress: "Clearly, 
  this is not a 'rush to the exits' that will jeopardise our security gains."
</p><p>
Mr Obama's speech was warmly welcomed by America's Nato allies. Speaking in 
  Afghanistan, William Hague, the Foreign Secretary, said: "We welcome 
  President Obama's announcement and it is in line with our own thinking. 
  There is clearly progress being made in Afghanistan and I've seen that for 
  myself on this visit."
</p><p>
Mr Hague confirmed that there were talks with the Taliban. Contacts do take 
  place," he said. "The United Kingdom will assist in that when it 
  can."
</p><p>
Speaking to senators in Washington, Hillary Clinton, the US Secretary of 
  State, described the contacts as "very preliminary outreach to members 
  of the Taliban", adding that "this is not a pleasant business" 
  but an essential element of ending the insurgency. 
</p><p>
Mr Obama told troops in New York state that there were "signs that the 
  Taliban may be interested in figuring out a political settlement that 
  ultimately is going to be critical in consolidating that country". 
</p><p>
President Nicolas Sarkozy of France announced a pullout "in a 
  proportional manner and in a calendar comparable to the withdrawal of 
  American reinforcements" while Guido Westerwelle, Germany's Defence 
  Minister, said that his country hoped "to be able to reduce our own 
  troop contingent for the first time" by the end of 2011. 
</p>]]></media-description>
      </media-content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8b04d8b3-36fe-4acb-b2e1-fa74690ea8b1</guid>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/internet/8595762/LulzSec-hackers-target-Arizona-police-website.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 03:15:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <title>LulzSec hackers target Arizona police website </title>
      <description><![CDATA[Computer hackers LulzSec who previously broke into a US Senate server and brought down the CIA webhasite have struck an Arizona police website their latest attack.]]></description>
      <media-thumbnail url="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01922/LulzSec_1922162g.jpg" width="140" height="90" />
      <media-content medium="document">
        <media-description><![CDATA[<div class="pubDate">Fri, 24 Jun 2011 03:15:52 +0100</div><div class="subTitle">LulzSec hackers target Arizona police website</div><div style="padding-top:5px;margin-bottom:10px">Computer hackers LulzSec who previously broke into a US Senate server and brought down the CIA webhasite have struck an Arizona police website their latest attack.</div><img src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01922/LulzSec_1922162e.jpg" onerror="ImageErrorHandler(this)" height="187" width="300" alt="LulzSec hackers target Arizona police website" />
                      <div id="offlineImg" style="display:none">Photo not displayed in offline mode</div><div class="caption">Hacking group LulzSec</div><p>Declaring that it opposed a tough anti-immigration law in Arizona, LulzSec said it was releasing documents that related to border control and other law enforcement activities. Its headline was "Chinga La Migra," Spanish for a more profane way of saying "Screw Immigration."</p><p>"We are aware of computer issues," said Steve Harrison, a spokesman for the Arizona Department of Public Safety, "We're looking into it. And of course we're taking additional security safeguards."</p><p>The Mexico border state passed a law last year ordering police to check the immigration status of anyone suspected to be in the United States illegally, in a bid to curb illegal immigration and border-related crime.</p><p>A majority of Americans supported the measure, but outraged opponents charged it was unconstitutional and would lead to the harassment of Hispanic-Americans, and called for an economic boycott of the desert state.</p><p>The most controversial parts of the law were blocked by a federal judge shortly before it came into effect last July, although Arizona is pursuing an appeal.</p><p>Lulz, a group of rogue hackers who have not been identified, posts the results of its hacks on Twitter, the microblogging site where the group has cultivated more than 240,000 followers.</p><p>So far LulzSec's publicised assaults on Sony Corp., the CIA, News Corp's Fox TV and other targets have mostly resulted in temporary disruptions of some websites and the release of user credentials.</p><p>There have been few arrests in the hacks. Earlier this week British police said that they had arrested a 19-year-old man on suspicion that he was connected to attacks on Sony, the CIA and a British police unit that fights organised crime.</p><p>Spanish police earlier this month apprehended three men on suspicion they helped Anonymous, a second rogue hacking group that has teamed up with LulzSec.</p><p>Security experts who have researched LulzSec's origins say it emerged from Anonymous, which became famous for attacking the companies and institutions that oppose WikiLeaks and its founder, Julian Assange. Anonymous also attacked Sony and governments around the globe that it considered oppressive.</p><p>LulzSec's members are believed to be scattered around the world, collaborating via secret internet chat rooms. Suspected leaders include hackers with the handles Kayla, Sabu and Topiary, security experts say.</p><p>The group's name is a combination of lulz, which is slang for laughs, and sec, which stands for security.</p><p> </p>]]></media-description>
      </media-content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2f2310e7-537c-484e-a621-286823ff9820</guid>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/topics/weather/8594467/Here-comes-the-sun-Britain-to-bask-in-summer-weather-at-last.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 15:28:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <title>Here comes the sun - Britain to bask in summer weather at last</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Temperatures expected to reach 90F over the weekend and next week.]]></description>
      <media-thumbnail url="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/rain_1928338g.jpg" width="140" height="90" />
      <media-content medium="document">
        <media-description><![CDATA[<div class="pubDate">Thu, 23 Jun 2011 15:28:05 +0100</div><div class="subTitle">Here comes the sun – Britain to bask in summer weather at last</div><div style="padding-top:5px;margin-bottom:10px">Britain is finally facing some summer weather with temperatures reaching nearly 90F over the weekend and through to next week.</div><img src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/rain_1928338e.jpg" onerror="ImageErrorHandler(this)" height="187" width="300" alt="Here comes the sun – Britain to bask in summer weather at last" />
                      <div id="offlineImg" style="display:none">Photo not displayed in offline mode</div><div class="caption">Those heading to Wimbledon will enjoy temperatures of 73F (23C) degrees on Saturday, a welcome change from the dull and showery weather it has experienced so far</div><p>
But the heat and humidity, which will beat Gibraltar and Istanbul, threatens 
  to go out with a bang, sparking thunderstorms across the country. 
</p><p>
Temperatures are expected to slowly creep up over the weekend hitting a high 
  of 82F (28C) on Sunday and then continuing to 90F (32C) on Monday. 
</p><p>
But the warm snap could lead to its own undoing, causing huge downpours, 
  thunder and lightning. 
</p><p>
Those heading to Wimbledon will enjoy temperatures of 73F (23C) degrees on 
  Saturday, a welcome change from the dull and showery weather it has 
  experienced so far. 
</p><p>
While mud caked Glastonbury revellers, who are in for another soaking today as 
  U2 take to the stage for the first night of the festival, can dry out in as 
  temperatures reach 75F (24C). 
</p><p>
John Hammond, a Met Office forecaster, said: "The cloud will thicken from 
  the south-west from today bringing a chance of rain, which is not the best 
  news for Glastonbury goers. 
</p><p>
This could also affect the last matches at Wimbledon as showers hit in the 
  evening. 
</p><p>
 "But once the rain has settled we will see things warm up for the 
  weekend, especially in the south-east of the country. 
</p><p>
Helen Chivers, a fellow forecaster, said there was a general north west and 
  south west divide. 
</p><p>
 "The weather will get a lot warmer as hot air moves north from the south 
  of the continent," she said. 
</p><p>
&ldquo;Saturday will start cloudy everywhere but the sun will come out in most 
  places away from the south and west coast and be very warm. 
</p><p>
&ldquo;London, the Midlands and East Anglia will have sunshine and temperatures up 
  to 73F (23C) and feel very humid. 
</p><p>
&ldquo;Sunday will be a dry, hot and humid day and could well see temperatures of 
  28C or 29C around London and 78F (26C) in northern England. 
</p><p>
&ldquo;Monday is likely to be slightly hotter, with possibly 32C in the south-east 
  and warm temperatures through the midlands. 
</p><p>
 "The north-east will be in the mid-20s but also risk showers, as will 
  the north-west, where it will be a little cooler. 
</p><p>
&ldquo;But such high temperatures bring the potential for heavy thunderstorms, most 
  likely in south-east and East Anglia at the end of Monday and into Tuesday, 
  which will see temperatures in the low-20s.&rdquo; 
</p><p>
The best of the weather will be on Sunday where temperatures in London and the 
  east of England will soar to 82F (28C) degrees. 
</p><p>
The temperature is expected to be several degrees higher than both Istanbul 
  and Gibraltar. 
</p><p>
Temperatures are set to be the hottest so far in 2011, beating the 82F (28.1C) 
  at Solent, Hants, on June 3. 
</p>]]></media-description>
      </media-content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">24e77605-afc8-49df-ab98-1c34be90a338</guid>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/tvandradio/8595426/Scene-in-Gordon-Ramsays-MasterChef-USA-faked.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 21:03:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <title>Scene in Gordon Ramsay's MasterChef USA faked</title>
      <description><![CDATA[At first glance, it seems hundreds of people turned up to win a spot on TV 
  show MasterChef USA and be shouted at by the Gordon Ramsay.]]></description>
      <media-thumbnail url="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/ramsey_1928855g.jpg" width="140" height="90" />
      <media-content medium="document">
        <media-description><![CDATA[<div class="pubDate">Thu, 23 Jun 2011 21:03:42 +0100</div><div class="subTitle">Scene in Gordon Ramsay's MasterChef USA faked</div><div style="padding-top:5px;margin-bottom:10px">At first glance, it seems that hundreds of people turned up to win a spot on the television show MasterChef USA and be shouted at by the celebrity chef Gordon Ramsay.</div><img src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/ramsey_1928855e.jpg" onerror="ImageErrorHandler(this)" height="187" width="300" alt="Scene in Gordon Ramsay's MasterChef USA faked" />
                      <div id="offlineImg" style="display:none">Photo not displayed in offline mode</div><div class="caption">The doctored scene in which someone in a green top apparently clapping can be seen twice, as can a woman in an orange jacket raising her arms in the air</div><p>
But something has been added to the mix. 
</p><p>
So few people turned up to the audition in Los Angeles that an opening shot 
  was faked.
</p><p>
One viewer spotted that parts of the crowd scene had been doctored and posted 
  a screen shot on Reddit, a social news website, pointing out the 
  duplications.
</p><p>
At least three groups of people have been replicated and stuck in the 
  background, to make the crowd look bigger.
</p><p>
In the poorly executed doctoring job someone in a green top apparently 
  clapping can be seen twice, as can a woman in an orange jacket raising her 
  arms in the air. A spokesman for Reveille Productions, which produces the 
  Fox Network show with Shine TV, admitted that the scene had been faked.
</p><p>
In a statement, the production company said: &ldquo;We have reviewed the footage and 
  it&rsquo;s clear that the scene was enhanced in post-production. 
</p><p>
&ldquo;We sincerely apologise to our viewers and hope that they still enjoyed the 
  show.&rdquo;
</p><p>
The clip broadcast on Monday featured interviews with people who claimed to 
  have travelled from every corner of America to be there, giving the 
  impression that hundreds of people had turned up to win the show&rsquo;s $250,000 
  first prize.
</p><p>
The episode appeared in the fifth episode of second series of MasterChef USA 
  in which Ramsay, with fellow judges Joe Bastianich and Graham Elliot, 
  whittle 100 of America&rsquo;s best amateur cooks down to one.
</p><p>
 The doctored footage will be an embarrassment for Ramsay who has had a 
  difficult time of late. 
</p><p>
It was revealed earlier this year that he had sacked his father-in-law, 
  Christopher Hutcheson from his company after discovering that he had raised 
  a secret family.
</p><p>
Ramsay, 44, fell out with his father-in&ndash;law in November after claims he had 
  borrowed &pound;1.5&thinsp;million from the company. Mr Hutcheson, who had played a 
  central role in Ramsay&rsquo;s success, denies any wrongdoing.
</p><p>
In September, an American chef who was told by Ramsay on his Kitchen 
  Nightmares television show that his restaurant would &ldquo;swim down the ------- 
  Hudson&rdquo; died after throwing himself into the river. Joseph Cerniglia, a 
  39-year-old father of three, jumped from the George Washington Bridge into 
  the Hudson which separates New York and New Jersey.
</p><p>
Ramsay has also suffered financial difficulties. He disclosed last year that 
  he had been forced to pour &pound;5&thinsp;million into his business at the end of 2008 
  to keep it afloat.
</p><p>
Amid a sharp decline in profits, he sacked staff, sold his Ferrari and gave up 
  restaurants in several cities including London, Prague and Cape Town.
</p>]]></media-description>
      </media-content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9cfff96b-32e9-4e90-869c-4fa32c65bcb4</guid>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/sarah-palin/8595440/Sarah-Palin-called-up-to-do-jury-service-in-Alaska.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 20:58:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <title>Sarah Palin called up to do jury service in Alaska </title>
      <description><![CDATA[Sarah Palin is to serve on a jury in an Alaska court, deciding the fate of an 
  as yet unidentified defendant.]]></description>
      <media-thumbnail url="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/palin_1928861g.jpg" width="140" height="90" />
      <media-content medium="document">
        <media-description><![CDATA[<div class="pubDate">Thu, 23 Jun 2011 20:58:12 +0100</div><div class="subTitle">Sarah Palin called up to do jury service in Alaska</div><div style="padding-top:5px;margin-bottom:10px">Sarah Palin is to serve on a jury in an Alaska court, deciding the fate of an as yet unidentified defendant.</div><img src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01928/palin_1928861e.jpg" onerror="ImageErrorHandler(this)" height="187" width="300" alt="Sarah Palin called up to do jury service in Alaska" />
                      <div id="offlineImg" style="display:none">Photo not displayed in offline mode</div><div class="caption">Mrs Palin disclosed she had been called up for jury service as she sought to dispel rumours that her 'One Nation' bus tour had been cancelled</div><p>
The former Republican vice-presidential candidate will be paid $25 (&pound;15.60) 
  per day, starting with the second day she reports to the courthouse, and 
  will also be reimbursed for mileage if the court is more than 30 miles from 
  her home.
</p><p>
Mrs Palin, the former governor of Alaska, disclosed she had been called up for 
  jury service as she sought to dispel rumours that her "One Nation" 
  bus tour had been cancelled.
</p><p>
She wrote on her Facebook page: "Sigh. Reports of tour demise are greatly 
  exaggerated. Why didn't anyone tell me? Oh, wait, that's because it hasn't 
  been cancelled.
</p><p>
"The coming weeks are tight because civic duty calls (like most everyone 
  else, even former governors get called up for jury duty) and I look forward 
  to doing my part just like every other Alaskan." 
</p><p>
Mrs Palin said she was "looking forward to hitting the open road again" 
  before the end of the summer, suggesting her jury service will not be 
  lengthy. She added: "The next leg of the tour continues when the time 
  comes."
</p><p>
Her Facebook post did not say when her jury service might start, or when or 
  where she had been summoned to serve. 
</p>]]></media-description>
      </media-content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">f53721a6-057b-45d1-bc8f-928d5af3c5e5</guid>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/science/science-news/8595968/Comfort-eating-linked-to-stress-in-hormone-study.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 09:03:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <title>Comfort eating linked to stress in hormone study </title>
      <description><![CDATA[The pressures of modern life could be behind the worldwide obesity epidemic 
  because stress drives people to comfort eating, scientists believe.]]></description>
      <media-content medium="document">
        <media-description><![CDATA[<div class="pubDate">Fri, 24 Jun 2011 09:03:42 +0100</div><div class="subTitle">Comfort eating linked to stress in hormone study</div><div style="padding-top:5px;margin-bottom:10px">The pressures of modern life could be behind the worldwide obesity epidemic because stress drives people to comfort eating, scientists believe.</div><p>
A US study has linked comfort eating to a hormone which increases the cravings 
  for fatty food, new research claims. 
</p><p>
Bingeing on sugary or fatty foods has long been connected to times of stress 
  or anxiety, with around two fifths of people thought to over-eat when under 
  pressure. 
</p><p>
It has also been blamed for the worsening obesity epidemic, with half of 
  British adults classed as overweight and almost one in five classified as 
  obese. 
</p><p>
US researchers found that levels of the ghrelin - the hunger hormone - 
  increased during prolonged periods of stress and appeared to fuel cravings 
  for fatty food. 
</p><p>
A team, from the University of Texas studied the ghrelin levels of mice 
  exposed to a variety of stressful situations who had free access to food. 
</p><p>
The study, published in the Journal of Clinical Investigation, concluded that 
  an increased level of ghrelin brought on by stress increased a mouse's 
  appetite. 
</p><p>
Dr Jeffrey Zigman, from the University of Texas medical centre said: "Many 
  people when stressed turn to high calorie 'comfort foods'. 
</p><p>
"Despite the contribution this behavior makes to the current obesity 
  epidemic, little is known about the molecules and nervous system circuits 
  that control it. 
</p><p>
"Insight into this could provide new targets for the development of 
  therapeutics to curb this potentially detrimental behavior.&rdquo;
</p>]]></media-description>
      </media-content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">798f076e-ab73-4f5c-9d00-3484602ef0d0</guid>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/science/space/8595514/Giant-asteroid-to-narrowly-miss-Earth.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 21:44:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <title>Giant asteroid to 'narrowly miss' Earth</title>
      <description><![CDATA[A newly discovered asteroid the size of an office block will narrowly miss the 
  Earth on Monday - coming 23 times closer than the moon.]]></description>
      <media-thumbnail url="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01688/asteroid_1688856g.jpg" width="140" height="90" />
      <media-content medium="document">
        <media-description><![CDATA[<div class="pubDate">Thu, 23 Jun 2011 21:44:22 +0100</div><div class="subTitle">Giant asteroid to 'narrowly miss' Earth</div><div style="padding-top:5px;margin-bottom:10px">A newly discovered asteroid the size of an office block will narrowly miss the Earth on Monday - coming 23 times closer than the moon.</div><img src="http://i.telegraph.co.uk/multimedia/archive/01688/asteroid_1688856e.jpg" onerror="ImageErrorHandler(this)" height="187" width="300" alt="Giant asteroid to 'narrowly miss' Earth" />
                      <div id="offlineImg" style="display:none">Photo not displayed in offline mode</div><div class="caption">Asteroid to narrowly miss next Monday, experts say.</div><p>
The space rock will reach within 11,000 miles of the its surface and give off 
  a light bright enough to be seen through a small telescope, experts said 
  today. 
</p><p>
It was only spotted on Wednesday by a robotic telescope in New Mexico that 
  scans the skies for such hazards. An alert was then put out yesterday by the 
  International Astronomical Union's Minor Planet Center in Massachusetts. 
</p><p>
The find was confirmed by Peter Birtwhistle, who has discovered dozens of 
  asteroids from his own UK observatory, with a photo taken from Great 
  Shefford in Berkshire. 
</p><p>
It will be daylight in the UK when the asteroid, which has been named 2011 MD, 
  makes its close encounter over the southern hemisphere. 
</p><p>
But astronomers in other parts of the world, such as South America, will be 
  able to watch it brighten and fade rapidly as it speeds through the starry 
  background. 
</p><p>
Asteroid 2011 MD is estimated to be between 10 and 50 yards wide. 
</p><p>
UK asteroid expert Dr Emily Baldwin said: "We are certain that it will 
  miss us, but if it did enter the atmosphere, an asteroid this size would 
  mostly burn up in a brilliant fireball, possibly scattering a few meteorites."
</p><p>
On November 8, a 400-metre wide asteroid weighing 50 million tons, called 2005 
  YU55, is expected to fly inside the orbit of the moon. 
</p><p>
Passing by at a distance of just 201,000 miles, the asteroid is the largest 
  object to approach the earth so close that we have known about in advance. 
</p>]]></media-description>
      </media-content>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>